Do you need an energising blast of water in the morning to wake you up for the day?
你需要早晨的一阵强劲水流来唤醒自己迎接活力满满的一天吗？
Or do you prefer a relaxing, warm shower in the evening to help you wind down as part of your nighttime routine?
还是更喜欢将洗个热水澡来帮助你放松作为晚间日常的一部分？
Maybe you just shower whenever you feel like it.
也许你只是随心所欲选择自己喜欢的时候去洗澡。
For something so many of us do, this topic is bound to divide opinion and stir up passion from both sides.
对于如此多人都要做的事情，这个话题必然会引发意见分歧，激起双方的热情。
But is one really better than the other?
但其中一种真的比另一种更好吗？
After a long day in the outside world, picking up pollutants and allergens on your skin and in your hair such as dust and pollen, a reasonable instinct would be to wash it all off before getting into bed.
在外面度过漫长的一天后，皮肤和头发上会沾上污染物和过敏原，如灰尘和花粉，一个合理的本能是在上床前把它们都洗掉。
That's what the evening shower enthusiasts would say.
这是晚间洗澡爱好者会说的话。
But, says microbiologist Primrose Freestone, no matter the air temperature, you will continue to sweat during the night.
但是，微生物学家普丽姆罗丝·弗里斯顿说，无论气温如何，你晚上都会继续出汗。
Bacteria on your skin then eat the nutrients in your sweat which is what causes BO.
然后皮肤上的细菌会吃掉汗液中的营养物质，这就是导致体味的原因。
Showering at night also doesn't stop you shedding dead skin cells.
晚上洗澡也无法阻止你脱落死皮细胞。
All this means you may not wake up feeling as fresh as you had hoped.
所有这些意味着你可能不会像希望的那样在醒来时感到神清气爽。
Showering in the morning, on the other hand, can help to remove dead skin cells, sweat or any bacteria you've picked up from your bed sheets.
另一方面，早上洗澡有助于去除死皮细胞、汗液或你从床单上沾到的任何细菌。"
"As a microbiologist, I am a day shower advocate," she says.
作为一名微生物学家，我是白天洗澡的拥护者，"她说。
But it's not all about cleanliness.
但这不仅仅是清洁的问题。
Nancy Rothstein, who calls herself The Sleep Ambassador, is concerned with sleep quality.
自称"睡眠大使"的南希·罗斯坦关注睡眠质量。
In her view, showering in the evening is an essential part of the 'preparing for bed' routine.
在她看来，晚上洗澡是"准备上床睡觉"例行程序中必不可少的一部分。"
"Call it an opportunity to shower yourself with mindfulness," she says.
把它当作一个正念沐浴的机会，"她说。
And research backs this up.
研究也支持这一点。
A systematic review of research published in Sleep Medicine Reviews in 2019 found nightly warm showering or bathing one to two hours before bedtime can improve sleep.
2019年发表在《睡眠医学评论》上的一项系统综述发现，睡前一到两小时洗热水澡或泡澡可以改善睡眠。
What it all boils down to is when you would like to feel freshest.
这一切归结为你希望什么时候感觉最清爽。
If you're someone who can't fully relax in bed until you've showered, you're likely an evening shower person.
如果你是那种洗完澡才能在床上完全放松的人，那么你很可能是支持晚上洗澡的人。
Whereas, if you can't stand the idea of putting on fresh, clean clothes in the morning when you haven't showered, then a morning rinse is probably more your style.
而如果你无法忍受早上没洗澡就穿上干净衣服的想法，那么早上冲洗可能更适合你的风格。
Whenever you choose to shower, Primrose Freestone says it's important to clean your bed sheets regularly to remove all the sweat, bacteria and dead skin cells that build up and can negatively affect the effectiveness of your showers.
无论你选择何时洗澡，普丽姆罗丝·弗里斯顿说，定期清洗床单很重要，以去除积聚的所有汗液、细菌和死皮细胞，这些会对你洗澡的效果产生负面影响。